# ALEXANDER THUO

## zanderthuo@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexander-thuo-998779122/

https://alexanderthuo.000webhostapp.com/

https://github.com/zanderthuo

#### PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a Frontend developer having 3 years of experience in the IT domain. Experienced in development of web applications with HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Reactjs, React Naive and Rest API. Moderate knowledge and experience with Nodejs and MongoDB. Good hands-on experience and knowledge of UI frameworks like React-bootstrap, Material UI and Antd.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Front-end Developer March 2020 - Present

### **Keja Cop Solutions**

Keja cop is a startup company providing property owners and managers with a world – class secure system to manage and rent their properties. I worked as a key member of its frontend development team. My work involves using multiple programming languages such as JavaScript, HTML and CSS, and libraries like Reactjs and Redux to code new interfaces, features and functionalities for the property management system. I was keen to detail what was given to me by the Project Manager and the Ui-Ux designer. I got hands-on experience in working remotely as the whole Tech team was remote.

## Front-end Developer September 2019 – March 2020

# **Getboda Technologies**

Getboda Technologies is a startup company providing on-demand logistics platforms who partner with experienced and reliable couriers to offer e-commerce, food delivery and courier services. I worked as a junior frontend developer. My work involved using HTML,CSS and Bootstrap to develop webpages for the company's website. I got hands-on experience in working with Git and Gitlab for Continuous Development.

## Technology Intern May 2019 – August 2019

#### **Safaricom PLC**

Safaricom PLC is the leading communications company in Kenya with the widest and strongest coverage. I worked as an intern at the Mpesa Department where my main role was to onboard new Mpesa customers to use Mpesa APIs on their applications. I also helped debug customers' applications who were integrating to Mpesa. I got experience in communicating with other developers over emails and phone calls during debugging.

## Web Developer and System Support May 2018 – May 2019

#### **Ubrica**

Designed, planned and developed responsive web pages for the eCommerce website(sokojanja) using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Prestashop. I analysed and enhanced the page speed performance using gtmetrix for the web pages I developed.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelors of Science in Information Technology May 2018 – Present**

Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology

# Diploma in Information Technology May 2015 - December 2017

Moi University

### **PROJECTS**

**Zao bora:** I got involved in a hackathon hosted by Andela where we were to develop a solution for 7 weeks which solves a problem on any SDG goal. Iwas in a team which developed a project called Zao Bora which is an online platform where people can register and be a part of a community that helps connect farmers with potential retailers and consumers.

**Citizen:** I got involved in a blockchain hackathon hosted by Celo blockchain where we were to develop solutions that will help solve corruption in the country. Citizen is a decentralized application built on top of Celo blockchain which helps to track procurement funds as well as government projects.

### **SKILLS**

HTML5,CSS3,JAVASCRIPT,BOOTSTRAP,REACTJS,MATERIAL UI, ANTD,REST API,NODEJS AND EXPRESSJS

GIT(GITHUB, BITBUCKET)

CI/CD

**TRELLO** 

**SLACK** 

#### AWARDS AND CERTIFICATIONS

BuildForSDG Challenge 2020 - Andela

Top Achiever Intern - Safaricom PLC 2019

DevC Training Participant - Andela 2019

BuildforSDG Challenge - Andela 2020

Openclassroom - Building Web Apps with REST APIs: Credential ID 8506283446

Openclassroom - Full-stack WIth Node is, Express and MongoDB: Credential ID 3486525409

Scrum Fundamentals Certified: Credential ID 721640 - Scrumstudy

React: Testing and Debugging - Linkedin

## **REFERENCES**

CALESTOR MAGERO, MANAGER - API PRODUCT, M-PESA PRODUCT DEVELOPMENT DEPARTMENT, SAFARICOM PLC

### /CMAGERO@SAFARICOM.CO.KE

WILLIAM OPUNDO, MANAGER - ONBOARDING SUPPORT, M-PESA PRODUCT DEVELOPMENT DEPARTMENT , SAFARICOM PLC,,

## /WOPUNDO@SAFARICOM.CO.KE

LEWIS MUNENE, LEAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER, GETBODA TECHNOLOGIES,

/MUNENE2379@GMAIL.COM